Rico Dowdle gets the ball He runs really
hard. He finds crease and he attacks.
He's so hard to bring down.
Touchdown, Carolina!
Rico, was Mike McCarthy the main reason
why you wanted to come to Pittsburgh?
Um, he's definitely one of the main
reasons um why I chose here. Um, when my
agent started talking to them and he was
like Pittsburgh the opportunity and
they reaching out but like I said
opportunity and coach McCarthy
definitely played a big factor into me
choosing Pittsburgh. What did you like
about him
>> [music]
>> as a coach? Um, he's a player's coach.
You know, one of the main things for me
just getting with him, I think it helped
me going through injuries in college. I
think he helped me get my body to his
best form and it's obviously helped me
get to where I'm at today. I think that
was one of the major things for me
though just injuries and and how he
[music] reacts with his players and
stuff like that. You've had back-to-back
1,000-yard seasons. Does that mean
anything to you or is that kind of you
know something a stat that's on the
outside and not that important to you?
Um, I I want to say it not necessarily
that doesn't mean something to me but I
mean it's kind of behind me now. Um,
and now it's can I go do it again? I got
to go do it again this year. It don't
doesn't really matter. I've gotten to
where I'm at now. I've did it. I'm
definitely proud that that I've did that
been able to accomplish that being an
undrafted and things like that but got
to continue to go put my best foot
forward and do it again. That's the
goal. You mentioned being undrafted.
Jaylen Warren was also undrafted. Is
there like a chip on your shoulder
because of that or is that kind of in
the past? Um,
I think it it definitely puts a chip on
your shoulder when you when you go
undrafted because for a guy like me
I always had to make the team fight for
my spot and just continue to keep
fighting. So, it definitely
kind of gives you the sense that you
were overlooked
and things like that but you know
everybody doesn't get drafted and
everybody has their own path but I
definitely would say it puts a chip on
your shoulder and just pushes you
to want to be better and work harder. It
gets you going. Your last head coach
Dave Canales, he said that you run with
tempo and violence. True?
Um, I can say there's some truth to
that. Yeah, tempo. Yeah, definitely want
to be patient a little bit try to feel
it out and go and then
be violent once I do get north and
south. So, yeah, definitely take
>> [music]
>> pride in being violent when I'm running
football. Has that always been the type
of running back you wanted to be from
you know high school to college before
coming to the NFL? Yeah, I definitely
say I always ran kind of even since I
was little. Yeah, I always
when you was a little kid when you see
somebody get ran over it's like oh like
truck stick. Yeah, so I definitely think
I've been [music] like that since I was
little. I saw in high school I believe
your senior year you had to move to
quarterback. Things went extremely well
for your team. What did that perspective
help in terms of being a running back
and seeing more from a quarterback's
point of view? Um, I think it helped me
like just understand defenses better
honestly. You know, high school it's not
the same level high school [music] as it
is in college and NFL but just getting
back there from a from seeing the
defense from a quarterback perspective I
have been able to do that and
I've been a third like emergency
quarterback for the past two for the
Cowboys and for
>> [music]
>> the Panthers last year. I've been an
emergency quarterback
on game days and things like that but I
definitely think it helps when I see the
defense and understand it a little bit
better. Last one for you, do you have a
favorite player or favorite running back
that you kind of grew up and liked the
way that they moved or how physical they
were?
Um,
the way they move physical physical I'll
say Adrian Peterson [music] for like
physicality, Marshawn Lynch, guys like
that. Physicality but my favorite
running back growing up was Reggie Bush.
[music] That's why I wear the number
five and things like that. That was my
favorite running back growing up. All
right. Thanks, Rico. Welcome to
Pittsburgh.
>> Thank you.